<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Greg Aster</title><description>Experimental Videographer &amp; Creator</description><link>https://dndiy.github.io/</link><language>en</language><item><title>Mega Meal Explained</title><link>https://dndiy.github.io/posts/mega-meal-explained/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dndiy.github.io/posts/mega-meal-explained/</guid><description>Why? Just why.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;relative pb-[56.25%]&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- 56.25% = 16:9 aspect ratio --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;iframe
src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4tR6VLaYJFA?controls=1&quot;
title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot;
frameborder=&quot;0&quot;
allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot;
referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot;
allowfullscreen
class=&quot;absolute top-0 left-0 w-full h-full&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;h1 class=&quot;text-center text-4xl font-bold text-neutral-50 mb-4&quot;&amp;gt;Thank you for choosing MEGA MEAL.&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center text-2xl text-neutral-400 mb-8&quot;&amp;gt;Home of the Froozie!&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;text-center text-lg text-neutral-400 mb-8&quot;&amp;gt;
Choose your size below.
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;text-center text-xl font-semibold mb-12&quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;em&gt;(&amp;lt;span class=&quot;text-[var(--primary)]&quot;&amp;gt;Kiddie&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;span class=&quot;text-blue-500&quot;&amp;gt;Medium&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;span class=&quot;text-red-500&quot;&amp;gt;ULTRA&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;)&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mega Meal Explained - &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;text-[var(--primary)]&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;Kiddie&lt;/em&gt; Size&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;bg-neutral-800 p-6 rounded-xl&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
It’s a fake trailer.&lt;br /&gt;
Sexy Hamburgler.&lt;br /&gt;
It gets weird.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mega Meal Explained - &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;text-blue-500&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;Medium Size&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;bg-neutral-800 p-6 rounded-xl&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
It’s a fake movie trailer—a parody of over-the-top films. A mysterious character &lt;em&gt;(redacted for legal reasons)&lt;/em&gt; is introduced in a cyberpunk city filled with holographic fast-food ads and corporate dystopia. The protagonist, clad in prison stripes and a fedora, exudes femme fatale energy as a deep, raspy voiceover narrates.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-gray-700 mt-4&quot;&amp;gt;
The trailer teases a world of intrigue, rebellion, and fast-food capitalism. It’s cheesy, self-aware, and exactly what you’d expect if your favorite fast-food mascots became sentient horrors in a future dystopian world.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-gray-700 mt-4&quot;&amp;gt;
The world these characters inhabit is dense and layered—like a delicious Froozie Shake. Don’t expect to catch every reference. It’s meal-messy, questionable, but oddly satisfying if you’re in the right mood.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mega Meal Explained - &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;text-red-500&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;em&gt;ULTRA Size&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;bg-neutral-800 p-6 rounded-xl&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
The video’s first few seconds are black. You hear a blaring siren. Then a moody reveal: a dark, rainy night, a maximum-security prison looming in the background, barbed wire, and water. Searchlights sweep the landscape, suggesting an escape. Text zooms in, setting our expectations: this is a parody trailer. The view transitions to a bustling futuristic dystopian megalopolis, seen from above. Holographic fast-food ads flash from skyscrapers as the music builds.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
A shot of legs walking slowly down a rainy alleyway teases a mysterious femme fatale. A deep, raspy voiceover kicks in, expressing hunger and desire. The camera pans over grimy streets and rundown restaurants. Finally, the backside of a provocatively dressed stranger—prison stripes, fedora, yellow gloves—walks among the crowds. A dramatic title slams onto the screen, punctuated by an explosion. It pauses a moment for the viewer to take it all in.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
The view returns to the city, now showing a mysterious CEO in a yellow jacket with a red afro, sitting in a position of power—overlooking his crumbling urban empire. Words, titles, and fake movie reviews pan over the scenes, insinuating that other humans have seen this, so you should too.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next Scenes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
An establishing shot of the giant corporate headquarters of the W Corporation leads into an empty, closed-down restaurant with a playplace. A sign pulls into focus: &lt;em&gt;No Adults in the Ball Pit&lt;/em&gt;. A low, wide shot of the restaurant from the ball pit’s perspective reveals a head with a hat slowly rising out of the balls. The music cues mystery and humor.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
A security guard walks down a hallway full of mannequins. The (&lt;strong&gt;redacted for legal reasons&lt;/strong&gt;) stands among them, absolutely still, blending in. The guard walks by, unaware. The (&lt;strong&gt;redacted for legal reasons&lt;/strong&gt;) breaks the fourth wall and winks at the camera.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
Next, a lab with a vault door labeled &lt;em&gt;Secret Recipe&lt;/em&gt;. Tension builds as we approach the door, then everything goes black. The music changes. A hamburger is sealed in a container, and a yellow-gloved hand reaches in, slowly pulling it out. The song has cool tropical vibes, playing as the scene fades out.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
The video takes the form of a movie trailer for a film that doesn’t exist. This format allows the creator to move the plot forward at a breakneck pace, introducing a world and storyline that leave room for further episodes.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
In this world, the (&lt;strong&gt;redacted for legal reasons&lt;/strong&gt;) character is clad in a bikini with prison stripes—a distinctive getup that’s not intended to sexualize her but is a nod to other characters and numerous tropes in different series and films, but reimagined with a strong female protagonist.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
The video’s quality is “fair,” with many glitches and imperfections. While it’s possible to hyper-focus on quality and create a seamless product, the labor involved as a solo creator makes that nearly impossible. Compromises were made to keep the project moving forward.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
Ultimately, the project suffers from the same issues as any indie production: &lt;strong&gt;budget, labor, and audience&lt;/strong&gt;. Larger studios have entire teams—writers, directors, artists, marketers, and equipment at the ready. A single creator working at this scale is bound to hit limits.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
In that sense, what’s been achieved so far is impressive, but will the series continue? Hopefully, but I’ve been down this road before. Overcoming the labor problem is like not having enough food to keep it alive—there’s no support system here, and the project will likely die, emaciated and forgotten, in some dark alley. The world at large won’t even notice its pathetic attempts to crawl. Friends will step over its mummified corpse, barely looking down, as the work of strangers is so much more sexy and mysterious, while people they know sit alone, slowly sinking into poverty, waiting for the last nail in the coffin to be hammered in.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p class=&quot;text-lg text-neutral-400&quot;&amp;gt;
Onward into the dark, rainy night, we continue pushing forward.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;text-center text-2xl font-bold mt-12&quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Would you like fries or Onion Rings?&lt;/strong&gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>The Melancholy adventures of Steamboat Willie</title><link>https://dndiy.github.io/posts/the-melencholy-adventures-of-steamboat-willie/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dndiy.github.io/posts/the-melencholy-adventures-of-steamboat-willie/</guid><description>A retrospective view on the project.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GS9bdSrCvfw?si=3-TWFDISeYHEQ7Bv&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Melancholy adventures of Steamboat Willie: A Retrospective on the Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple, somewhat cynical observation: if you create something entirely new and unique, it often struggles to gain traction - while parodies or familiar characters tend to engage audiences and get more attention. It’s a frustrating reality of creative work, and something I decided to shine a light on - and lean ironically into. &lt;em&gt;Steamboat Willie&lt;/em&gt; had just entered the public domain, and the idea of updating and colorizing it felt like a perfect blend of nostalgia, experimentation, and irony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post serves as a behind-the-scenes look at the project’s creation, from its conceptualization to its execution, and reflects on the lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept and Motivation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to use &lt;em&gt;Steamboat Willie&lt;/em&gt; as the foundation was strategic. The cartoon’s entry into the public domain provided an opportunity to showcase my editing and graphics ability. Additionally, Walt Disney’s controversial legacy and the Disney Corporation’s history of intellectual property theft made the project a good target for parody and commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production of &lt;em&gt;Steamboat Willie&lt;/em&gt; was a labor-intensive process that involved several stages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial (failed) Attempts&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
The first cuts of the project were a straightforward edits of the original cartoon. I quickly realized that this approach was time-consuming and unsustainable. To streamline the process, the decicion was made to break the project into smaller, bite-sized episodes, which could be released incrementally on social media and stitched together later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rotoscoping and Colorization&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Rotoscoping - tracing each character frame by frame - and the colorization was the bulk of the labor. It felt necessary to use original character lines to retain the charm of the original animation.
&amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/TlmBrhCwX_I?si=dH5iKUVLSFurjvSq&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;modestbranding=1&amp;amp;rel=0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compositing and Backgrounds&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
New backgrounds were created or modified to fit the 16:9 aspect ratio - as the original 5:4 frames were too small. Some scenes required “outpainting” to fill in extended areas. Stock video from my recent trip to Alaska was used extensively to create these backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Integration&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
The underwater sequences featuring Black Pete utilized AI-generated visuals. These scenes were intentionally surreal and artificial. It was a cheeky nod to the idea of a “fake” world - serving as a addirional meta commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Color Correction and Consistency&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
To unify the disparate visual elements,  extreme color grading across the entire project was used to ensure a consistent look and feel despite the varied sources of the footage.
&amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3rTQliK1MAU?si=SMEKRiJ_Rlmpq1oT&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;modestbranding=1&amp;amp;rel=0&quot;
title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sound Design&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Squeaky toys, radio static, and a parakeet were used. Whale noises for the mermaid. Boat horn for the cow, The music was original, created using an MIDI keyboard and LMMS music studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./The-Melencholy-Adventures-of-Steamboat-Willie/Blender.png&quot; alt=&quot;View of boat n blender compositing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Themes and Narrative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its heart, the video was about life, loss, and acceptance. The steamboat, named &lt;em&gt;Charon&lt;/em&gt; (after the ferryman of the dead in Greek mythology), symbolized life’s journey. The river it traveled represented the passage of time, leading the characters—and, by extension, the audience—toward the inevitable end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the episodes, the characters grew increasingly detached from one another, reflecting the inevitability of separation and mortality. The emotional arc of the story was intended to evoke a sense of melancholy and introspection, contrasting sharply with the lighthearted expectations of the original cartoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges and Reflections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Shots&lt;/strong&gt;:  These proved particularly challenging, the last scenes weren&apos;t particularly engaging, and required extensive reworking - eventually being condensed for the final cut.
&amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jGCAgHO-oCQ?si=4rYzPYcDph1ztXze&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;modestbranding=1&amp;amp;rel=0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;/strong&gt;: The sheer volume of labor involved in producing each episode made it clear that creating content of this scale solo was unsustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience Reception&lt;/strong&gt;: While the project achieved moderate success (with an estimated 3,000 views across platforms - not bad, not viral), many viewers failed to pick up on the deeper themes and details embedded in the work. It highlighted the gap between creator intent and audience interpretation - something I see often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested in the technical aspects of the project, here’s a breakdown of the tools and locations used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filming Locations&lt;/strong&gt;: Portland, Oregon, and Kenai Fjords, Alaska.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equipment&lt;/strong&gt;: Zoom H4N audio recorder, Panasonic GH6 camera with a Zeiss Flektogon 35/2.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software&lt;/strong&gt;: DaVinci Resolve (editing), Blender 3D (3D modeling), ComfyUI (AI generation), Audacity (audio editing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music&lt;/strong&gt;: Arturia KeyLab digital keyboard and LMMS music studio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back I’m appreciative of how much it taught me. It was a project born out of curiosity, frustration, and a desire to create something meaningful. It reminded me why I create: not for the views or the likes, but for the joy of bringing something into the world that didn’t exist - but needs to exist. Despite its flaws, it has a place in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A poignant sentiment, one that captures the essence of &lt;em&gt;The Melancholy adventures of Steamboat Willie&lt;/em&gt; - fleeting, imperfect, exploration of life, art, and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Remember me. I was.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>New Website Starts Today.</title><link>https://dndiy.github.io/posts/new/new/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dndiy.github.io/posts/new/new/</guid><description>A new website and a central location for my content.</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Hello!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the general hellscape of the internet, social media, and the world at large, I figured it was wise to teach myself html coding, make a time machine, travel to 1996 and bang out a sweet website in my mother&apos;s basement. The purpose is to create a central repository for my content, and own my data. There will be more features, updates, and posts to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who is this Weirdo? What is this Place?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t worry this is a safe space! I will never ask for your home address and social security number.
Gregory Aster is a filmmaker, animator, and storyteller with a penchant for the bizarre, the experimental, and the deeply nostalgic. He spent 23 years as a mechanic - 10 as a certified technician and manager, then 13 as a business owner. Having retired from the trade, he now devotes all his time to creative media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His creative work blends cyberpunk, cosmic horror, and absurdist humor - drawing inspiration from old-school sci-fi, westerns, and the strange corners of pop culture. From dystopian fast-food conspiracies to interdimensional smugglers, his projects thrive on mystery, aesthetic weirdness, and an undercurrent of melancholy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg has more than a decade of experience in local TV production, contract videography, and a lifetime of hands-on problem-solving. He is fluent in Blender3d, Davinci Resolve, can code a bit, works with ComfyUI, and experiments with cutting-edge video tools. When he&apos;s not crafting surreal narratives, he&apos;s either running around drinking too much coffee, beating on a machine with a hammer, or considering the deep philosophical and moral quandaries of science fiction, romance novels, and historical literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Current and Upcoming Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m actively working on several projects, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mega Meal&lt;/strong&gt; - A dystopian cyberpunk cosmic horror series exploring themes of food, mystery, nostalgia, and loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Damn Website&lt;/strong&gt; - Whew! What a headache!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Housework and Furniture Building&lt;/strong&gt; - Life and duty calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future Website Plans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternate Universe Theme&lt;/strong&gt; - This website is to include an alternate universe theme tied to a cosmic horror entity named Merkin (&lt;em&gt;In Progress&lt;/em&gt;). You may notice the absent dark/light mode switches that transport you to a parallel version of this space - a nod to my fascination with alternate realities and strange timelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newsletter Sign-Up&lt;/strong&gt; - Sign up for my upcoming newsletter &lt;em&gt;that does not exist yet&lt;/em&gt; to stay updated on new projects, behind-the-scenes content - there is nothing exclusive about this - but if you want to stay in the know you now know you don&apos;t have that option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog Philosophy&lt;/strong&gt; - Expect a mix of content here - project updates, reflections on creative life, inspiration behind stories, and occasional commentary on art and media. I would like to focus on community and listen to feedaback. so, I’d love to hear your thoughts on my work! Feel free to reach out with, ideas, or suggestions. This space is as much about community as it is about creativity. Speaking of community - if you want me to share and distribute your creative projects here - talk to me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the works&lt;/strong&gt;  A newsletter section, more articles, art, a contact page, a resume, consolidated content. If you have any recommendations on website direction, or spot any issues with this space, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This website is where all of that comes together - a home for projects, ideas, and whatever else comes next. Stay tuned for more updates and sneak peeks as these projects evolve. If you want to collaborate, reach out! I never have enough time - but I can always make time for more - it’s a weird interdimensional nexus I exist in.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and thanks for being awesome!
Greg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./uwantsumart.gif&quot; alt=&quot;uwantsumart.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How Does AI Affect Creative Expression and the Value of Art?</title><link>https://dndiy.github.io/posts/navigating-the-ai-age-of-art/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dndiy.github.io/posts/navigating-the-ai-age-of-art/</guid><description>Exploring the Divide: Art, Isolation, and the Digital Future</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 1996 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Navigating the AI Age of Art&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a shift in culture recently, and now AI is everywhere. We are talking about it constantly. It seems everywhere I turn, people are polarized and fired up about it. But truthfully, none of this matters. With new things, there is alaways turmoil. AI is no different - people are upset. People talk, torches and pitchforks are raised, fingers point, and accusations fly abound. I find all this really unfortunate and hope the turmoil dies down soon - but my heels are dug in, and I&apos;m ready for the long haul either way. This seems to be exaggerated by a generational divide, and this ia also nothing new. This argument is old - painters and cameras, horses and cars, practical effects and computer graphics. And whether for or against - we all use AI every day, constantly. We are swimming in AI - and at the same time, AI isn’t really what the hype says it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The swimming in AI I refer to is our phones, map navigation, texting, media feeds, TV, ads, and more. There is no escape. We are drowning - and to survive in this sea of talking robots, you must understand how to use AI to be empowered and navigate the changing currents, and to understand this - you must understand that AI isn’t really AI. It’s just another tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let’s Deal with the Preconceptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. Is AI actually Artificial Intelligence?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;No.&lt;/strong&gt; AI cannot think. If AI could think, then it would be real “AI.” What people generally call “AI” is just a branding term for statistical models called “neural networks” (which is another branding term in itself). These models can get extremely complex - so much so that it’s difficult to differentiate between AI-generated content and human-created work. Despite this, any “AI” generated work you see on the internet has a human behind it - because AI is not autonomus - it cannot think - anything it does is guided by human hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. Is AI art theft?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;No, not inherently.&lt;/strong&gt; AI can’t steal any more than a paintbrush or a camera can. However, AI art, with its complex tools and abilities to mimic, can be used to steal and deceive. Just like any tool, it is possible be used for good and bad. The stories of theft make great headlines, so fear and anger have been misdirected at the machines rather than the people abusing them. The ones using AI to mimic and deceive are the problem - not the average user, and certainly not the technology itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. Will AI take my job?&lt;/strong&gt;
Yes! If it hasn’t already taken your job, it probably will - or at least impact it severely. To understand this, we only need to look at history - I use the Industrial Revolution for analogy. Many people worked in factories then - these people became unemployed when a machine took their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what can we do about the robots taking our jobs? Luddites tried to do something - famously, they destroyed the factory machines during the Industrial Revolution. They became symbolic of technological resistance and eventually got enshrined in language as someone incompetent with technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With machines being able to produce art cheaply - and in some cases better and faster than the working artist - what do we do? The answer to this question is nothing new: control the machines that produce better and faster. Be on top of the wave rather than crushed underneath it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Does AI Affect Creative Expression and the Value of Art?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we stand out in this vast ocean of content? How can we keep up with the speed of its prodcution? How do we reconcile the seemingly pointless nature of creative expression? What is our value in a world where machines can generate art at the push of a button? The answer is art never had any value. It&apos;s all products, scarcity, and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re asking these questions in the first place, you are probably thinking more about capitalism and less about art. When you create something truly meaningful, it shouldn&apos;t be about the product or the scarcity of it - it should be about the expression and intent of what you are doing. You should be making something because you want to, because it is beautiful, because it deserves to exist. The medium it was made with should not matter. If you&apos;re produce because you want to commodify something, you are a producer. If you’re worried or upset that you can’t sell something, or that someone might devalue something that has no intrinsic scarcity - a thing that can be produced infinitely without effort - you can&apos;t really put a price tag on it. To desire to stop this flow, or to inflate its worth is a lie. People who produce only to sell let internalized capitalism govern their work, and they are slaves to a system that ironically treats them like a commodity themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of the food replicator in Star Trek - did chefs cry and lament because they lost their jobs? In that utopian future, they didn’t. Cooking became a choice rather than a necessity. The real problem we face isn’t AI or automation - it’s capitalism. We’re thinking about art as a commodity, and we can’t commodify something that has no scarcity. The unfortunate side effect of this is that artists go hungry in a system that values only what is scarce, and digital media can be replicated infinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advent of AI in art, scarcity can be less of a thing. You no longer have to be beautiful, you no longer have to cry and suffer for something - you can just, at the flick of a switch, make anything you want. We should really be making art not because we need more content in this world, but because we like art. Having no value attached to it is actually a boon. It allows someone to create without restriction. In the end, only individuals who rely on selling themselves or need other people for validation are the ones in danger of losing their power and prestige. If you determine that there’s something in this world that is missing for you - something that you want - whether it is a finished product or simply enjoying the act of creation - then make that thing. That is independence and power. The medium doesn’t matter. The medium is just a means, a tool. Tools will always change - but creation is timeless. True creators don’t get lost in the arms race - they simply make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can’t replace real creators because they define what creation is. The only thing AI does is challenge the tradition of production. The gulf between creators and producers is changing. If an artist chooses to use AI as a tool, it doesn’t make them any less of an artist. It simply means they’re using a different brush on their canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True art should be free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI is not a threat to the artist, but it is a threat to art as a product - and I&apos;m not sure its a bad thing. Maybe, without value attached to it, art can be free and accessible to people without means. Don’t restrict or cut out people who enjoy these things. This divide is putting people on the wrong side of history. Look to the future - whether that future is liberating or dystopian depends entirely on who controls it. So, ride the wave, understand it. If you don’t like the medium, don’t judge someone who does. And if you want less AI - put down that phone, stop typing, don’t use a map. Instead, look around - get lost outside, talk to someone real, paint, dance, enjoy a sunset - and if you’re an artist, consider asking yourself questions - questions about why you do what you do, your value, your personal expression, and what freedom to make whatever you want without restriction really means.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>