<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Greg Aster</title><description>Experimental Videographer &amp; Creator</description><link>https://dndiy.github.io/</link><language>en</language><item><title>The Melancholy adventures of Steamboat Willie</title><link>https://dndiy.github.io/posts/the-melencholy-adventures-of-steamboat-willie/the-melencholy-adventures-of-steamboat-willie/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dndiy.github.io/posts/the-melencholy-adventures-of-steamboat-willie/the-melencholy-adventures-of-steamboat-willie/</guid><description>A Retrospective view on the Project.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GS9bdSrCvfw?si=3-TWFDISeYHEQ7Bv&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Melancholy adventures of Steamboat Willie: A Retrospective on the Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project started with a simple, somewhat cynical observation: if you create something entirely new and unique, the content often struggles to gain traction, while parodies or familiar characters tend to engage audiences more effectively and get attention. It’s a frustrating reality of creative work, and one I decided to lean ironically into. &lt;em&gt;Steamboat Willie&lt;/em&gt; had just entered the public domain, and the idea of updating and colorizing it felt like a perfect blend of nostalgia and experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog post serves as a behind-the-scenes look at the project’s creation, from its conceptualization to its execution, and reflects on the lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept and Motivation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to use &lt;em&gt;Steamboat Willie&lt;/em&gt; as the foundation was strategic. The cartoon’s entry into the public domain provided an opportunity to showcase my editing and graphics ability. Additionally, Walt Disney’s controversial legacy and the Disney Corporation’s history of intellectual property theft made the project a target for parody and commentary.
The tension between critique and adoration felt like fertile ground to work with as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production of &lt;em&gt;Steamboat Willie&lt;/em&gt; was a labor-intensive process that involved several stages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial (failed) Attempts&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
My first cut of the project was a straightforward edit of the original cartoon. I quickly realized that this approach was time-consuming and unsustainable. To streamline the process, I decided to break the project into smaller, bite-sized episodes, which could be released incrementally on social media and stitched together later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rotoscoping and Colorization&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Rotoscoping - tracing each character frame by frame - and the colorization was the bulk of the labor. It felt necessary to use original character lines to retain the charm of the original animation.
&amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/TlmBrhCwX_I?si=dH5iKUVLSFurjvSq&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;modestbranding=1&amp;amp;rel=0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compositing and Backgrounds&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
New backgrounds were created or modified to fit the 16:9 aspect ratio, as the original 5:4 frames were too small. Some scenes required “outpainting” to fill in extended areas. Stock video from my recent trip to Alaska was used extensively to create these backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Integration&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
The underwater sequences featuring Black Pete utilized AI-generated visuals. These scenes were intentionally surreal and artificial. It was a cheeky nod to the idea of a “fake” world - serving as a meta commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Color Correction and Consistency&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
To unify the disparate visual elements, I applied extreme color grading across the entire project to ensure a consistent look and feel despite the varied sources of the footage.
&amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3rTQliK1MAU?si=SMEKRiJ_Rlmpq1oT&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;modestbranding=1&amp;amp;rel=0&quot;
title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sound Design&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
Squeaky toys, radio static, and a parakeet were used. Whale noises for the mermaid. Boat horn for the cow, The music was original, created using an MIDI keyboard and LMMS music studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./Blender.png&quot; alt=&quot;View of boat n blender compositing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Themes and Narrative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its heart, the video was about life, loss, and acceptance. The steamboat, named &lt;em&gt;Charon&lt;/em&gt; (after the ferryman of the dead in Greek mythology), symbolized life’s journey. The river it traveled represented the passage of time, leading the characters—and, by extension, the audience—toward the inevitable end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the episodes, the characters grew increasingly detached from one another, reflecting the inevitability of separation and mortality. The emotional arc of the story was intended to evoke a sense of melancholy and introspection, contrasting sharply with the lighthearted expectations of the original cartoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges and Reflections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Shots&lt;/strong&gt;:  These proved particularly challenging, requiring extensive reworking and eventually being condensed for the final cut.
&amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jGCAgHO-oCQ?si=4rYzPYcDph1ztXze&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;modestbranding=1&amp;amp;rel=0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;/strong&gt;: The sheer volume of labor involved in producing each episode made it clear that creating content of this scale solo was unsustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience Reception&lt;/strong&gt;: While the project achieved moderate success (with an estimated 3,000 views across platforms - not bad, not viral), many viewers failed to pick up on the deeper themes and details embedded in the work. It highlighted the gap between creator intent and audience interpretation - something I see often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested in the technical aspects of the project, here’s a breakdown of the tools and locations used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filming Locations&lt;/strong&gt;: Portland, Oregon, and Kenai Fjords, Alaska.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equipment&lt;/strong&gt;: Zoom H4N audio recorder, Panasonic GH6 camera with a Zeiss Flektogon 35/2.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software&lt;/strong&gt;: DaVinci Resolve (editing), Blender 3D (3D modeling), ComfyUI (AI generation), Audacity (audio editing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music&lt;/strong&gt;: Arturia KeyLab digital keyboard and LMMS music studio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back I’m appreciative of how much it taught me. It was a project born out of curiosity, frustration, and a desire to create something meaningful. It reminded me why I create: not for the views or the likes, but for the joy of bringing something into the world that didn’t exist, but needed to exist, and has a place in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Remember me. I was.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A poignant sentiment, one that captures the essence of &lt;em&gt;The Melancholy adventures of Steamboat Willie&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a fleeting, imperfect, exploration of life, art, and memory.
That’s enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How Does AI Affect Creative Expression and the Value of Art?</title><link>https://dndiy.github.io/posts/how/how/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dndiy.github.io/posts/how/how/</guid><description>Exploring the Divide: Art, Isolation, and the Digital Future</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;How Does AI Affect Creative Expression and the Value of Art?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is drowning in noise—
Soapbox articles, endless ads, clickbait. And now, with the advent of AI, the internet is overflowing with junk art and auto-generated articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we stand out in this impossibly vast ocean of content? How do we reconcile the seemingly pointless nature of creative expression? What is our value in a world where machines can generate art at the push of a button?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./pic1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Abstract depiction of AI-generated art&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What It Means to Be a Creator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many of us, there’s a process to creating: observing something beautiful, listening to music, revisiting old projects, cutting out distractions, and waiting for inspiration to strike. Some call it flow, others call it a Muse, inspiration, or simply work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some cursed wretches, creativity is not an option—it’s a compulsion. It screams inside, demanding to be released, only to be replaced by the next idea once expelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you sit down. You create. Possessed by the strings of some unseen puppet master, your fingers move in a trance, lost in the process. You rant, you refine, you shape something from nothing. But then, the inevitable question arises—what do you do with what you’ve made?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we even need more content? The internet is already overflowing. Now, with AI, bots can generate lengthy dissertations on demand. Anything I produce has no value. No purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the answer, at least for me, is simple: &lt;strong&gt;the act of creation is the point.&lt;/strong&gt; The act of creation is the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creators vs. Producers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand AI’s impact on creativity, we first have to recognize that there are different types of creatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some love the process—the act of making, the engagement, the doing. Others simply want the end result: their name on something, to produce something without having truly built it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That, to me, putting your name on something is not creativity. It’s a red flag when someone seeks only credit but has no love for the work. These people aren’t creators; they’re &lt;strong&gt;producers&lt;/strong&gt;. They want the benefits of art without touching its soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI is a gift to these producers. It allows them to flood the internet with soulless, synthetic content—images, stories, and music generated at inhuman speeds, devoid of struggle, meaning, or intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is a shining light through all this darkness—AI &lt;strong&gt;can’t replace real creators&lt;/strong&gt; because they define what creation is. The only thing AI does is challenge traditional production. The gulf between creators and producers hasn’t changed. If an artist chooses to use AI as a tool, it doesn’t make them any less an artist. It simply means they’re using a different brush on their canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./pic2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Human artist painting alongside AI-generated imagery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Art as a Product—Or Is It?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some claim AI-generated art is theft. But what, exactly, has been stolen? Do you steal every time you take a photo? When you draw a smiley face? When you mix colors you didn’t invent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All art is built on what came before. That’s how learning works. If what you create is shaped by your experiences, then it’s an original work—not theft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real issue isn’t theft—it’s &lt;strong&gt;devaluation&lt;/strong&gt;. AI makes art cheap. It produces faster than any human ever could, and in many cases, the results are better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, after much thought, I’ve come to a dismal conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Art has no value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For something to hold monetary value, it must be both in demand and in limited supply. But how do you value something when its supply is infinite? The answer—if one were to define art with calculus—is that the limit of infinity approaches zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Art, Scarcity, and Capitalism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI devaluing the product of art isn’t new. Technology has always made it easier to reproduce and cheapen artistic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manufactured scarcity. Copyrights. NFTs. Artificial barriers to replication. These transform art into a commodity, giving it artificial value at the expense of its soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;True art should be free.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in a capitalist system, free things hold no value. The system forces artists into survival mode, demanding they turn their work into a product—or starve. The artist who commodifies their work succeeds; the artist who simply creates is left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some fear that AI will destroy art. But AI isn’t the real problem—a &lt;strong&gt;system that does not support creators&lt;/strong&gt; is the problem. This is the true restriction of creative expression. Call it what you will—capitalism, corporations, fascism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI is here.&lt;/strong&gt; We are swimming in it. It dominates our media, our text, and our algorithms. The question isn’t whether AI will replace artists, but &lt;strong&gt;who will control the product of art.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./pic3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AI-generated art being mass-produced&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I Use Less AI Than You Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stay well-versed in the latest AI trends and use it consciously, in sips and with precision. I use it differently. I control my data. My ideas are my own. AI is my tool, not a master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, those who disparage AI the most are often the ones already enslaved by it—fed the same algorithmic opinions, guided by invisible hands, believing their thoughts are original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Art is not real&lt;/strong&gt;—not in the way we think. It’s an amalgamation of ideas, a spectrum between product and concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A painting on a wall—is that art? A breathtaking sunset—does it cease to be meaningful because it cannot be bought?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time art is sold, it enters a system of oppression. But we all have the right to live, to create, to prosper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporations will always cash in. They don’t care. Meanwhile, smaller artists fight over authenticity while the real profiteers laugh from above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI is not the death of art. &lt;strong&gt;It is the death of art as a product.&lt;/strong&gt; And maybe that’s not a bad thing. Maybe, for the first time in centuries, &lt;strong&gt;art can be free again.&lt;/strong&gt; But whether that future is liberating or dystopian depends entirely on who controls it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you’re an artist, ask yourself—&lt;strong&gt;are you in control of your work, or is the algorithm in control of you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>New Website Starts Today.</title><link>https://dndiy.github.io/posts/new/new/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dndiy.github.io/posts/new/new/</guid><description>A new website, and a central location for my content.</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the general hellscape of the internet, social media, and the world at large, I figured it was wise to create a central repository for my content. This is day one. There will be more features, updates, and posts to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is Gregory Aster?
Gregory Aster is a filmmaker, animator, and storyteller with a penchant for the bizarre, the experimental, and the deeply nostalgic. He spent 23 years as a mechanic 10 as a certified technician and manager, then 13 as a business owner - he retired from the trade and dove headfirst into the world of creative media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work blends cyberpunk, cosmic horror, and absurdist humor, drawing inspiration from old-school sci-fi, westerns, and the strange corners of pop culture. From dystopian fast-food conspiracies to interdimensional smugglers, his projects thrive on mystery, aesthetic weirdness, and an undercurrent of melancholy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg has experience in local TV production, contract videography, and a lifetime of hands-on problem-solving. He is fluent in Blender, works with ComfyUI for AI-assisted animation, and experiments with the latest, cutting edge video tools. When he&apos;s not crafting surreal narratives, he&apos;s either running, learning French, or considering a side quest into trucking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is where all of that comes together—a home for projects, ideas, and whatever else comes next. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>